The cozy English.
Learn English slowly.
Close your eyes for a moment, or just let your gaze soften on something still.
Welcome back to the cozy English.
I'm Emma, and as I was walking to the studio this morning,
I noticed how the light was catching the dust motes in the air,
just tiny golden specks dancing in the sun.
It reminded me that even the air we breathe is full of little movements we usually ignore.
I decided right then to let today be whatever it needs to be without forcing a perfect plan.
I'm just here in this chair with my favorite mug and a very quiet heart.
Hi, Emma, and hello to everyone joining our circle today.
It's funny you say that.
I'm sitting here across from you, and I can feel that stillness you're talking about.
Usually, my mind is a checklist of things I haven't done yet,
but today, I'm trying to just listen to the sound of the city outside the window,
that distant that usually feels like pressure,
but today just feels like a lullaby.
It's nice to just breathe for a second before we dive into our thoughts.
It really is.
But I have to be honest with you, Daniel, and with everyone listening.
This stillness is something I've had to fight for.
For years, I used to hide in the editing phase of my life.
I would record a podcast episode
or write a lesson and then obsess over it for weeks,
convinced that if I just changed one more word, it would finally be ready.
I told myself I was being a professional, but really, I was just terrified.
That sounds exactly like where I am right now.
I spent the last three hours trying to edit a single image for our community post.
I kept changing the font, moving the logo by one millimeter, then changing it back.
Every time I thought I was finished, a little voice said, it's not quite right yet.
If you post this, people will think you don't care.
So I just didn't post it.
I've been sitting in this calm studio, but my brain is exhausted from a battle over one millimeter.
That little voice is the architect of what I call the golden cage of excellence.
We tell ourselves that our perfectionism is a virtue, that it shows how much we care about quality.
But if we look closer, that cage is built out of fear.
We stay inside the polishing phase because as long as the work isn't done, it can't be judged.
Perfectionism is often just procrastination in a fancy suit.
It feels like excellence, but it functions like a prison.
Procrastination in a fancy suit.
That's a painful realization.
I've always been proud of my high standards, thinking that by being my own harshest critic, I was ensuring quality.
But you're right.
I'm not producing quality.
I'm just producing silence.
I feel like if I speak English with a mistake
or if I post a design
that isn't 100% perfect, I'm failing.
But the result of trying to be 100% perfect is that I'm 0% finished.
Is my excellence actually just a way to avoid the vulnerability of being seen?
Exactly.
Spend effort only on what's truly worth it,
and your energy is much better spent on connecting with people than on moving a logo by a millimeter.
A private life is a happy life means realizing
that the perfect version of you
that the world sees is often the most lonely and exhausted version of you.
The beauty of life happens in the messy parts, the parts we try to hide because they aren't perfect yet.
I think I'm ready to take off the fancy suit, Emma.
I'm tired of being perfectly silent.
I want to be imperfectly active.
Before we move on, I want to invite everyone to join us in this journey.
If you find these conversations helpful, please hit that subscribe button.
It helps us keep the lights on in this cozy corner.
And for those of you who want to really sit with these ideas
and study the language we use,
you can download the full PDF script in the description.
It's a great way to follow along without the pressure of being perfect at listening.
Now I want you to ask yourself a hard question.
What is the thing you are currently pretending to improve
or perfect, but in reality, are just avoiding the fear of finishing it?
So, Emma, if I take off this fancy suit of perfectionism, what am I left with?
The idea of good enough honestly feels a bit dangerous to me.
If I settle for good enough in my English studies
or my work, doesn't that lead to a slippery slope of mediocrity?
I've always been taught that if a job is worth doing, it's worth doing right.
If I start accepting 80% effort, I'm worried that I'll eventually stop caring altogether.
How do you distinguish between being healthy with your standards and just being lazy?
That's a fair concern, but there's a massive difference between good enough and lazy.
Lazy is not caring about the result.
Good enough is caring so much about the outcome that you refuse to let perfectionism stop you from reaching it.
Think about the Pareto principle or the eighty twenty rule.
Often, 80% of your results come from just 20% of your effort.
The last 20% of perfection takes an enormous amount of energy, but adds very little real value.
Spend effort only on what's truly worth it, and usually, useful beats flawless.
Useful beats flawless.
I like the sound of that, but it's hard to trust.
I feel like my high standards are a shield that protects me from criticism.
If I'm perfect, nobody can hurt my feelings or tell me I'm wrong.
But that shield is heavy, Daniel, and it doesn't actually work.
Let me give you a real example.
Last month, you needed to ask that guest speaker for an interview.
Right?
You were overthinking that email for three days.
Finally, you just got tired, typed a quick message with a couple of typos, and hit send.
It wasn't impressive.
It was just understandable.
And what happened?
He replied in five minutes and said yes.
He didn't even mention the typos.
He just cared that the message was clear and that I was respectful.
I guess the flawless version wouldn't have gotten a different result.
It just would have taken me three days longer to get it.
Exactly.
That is a good enough win.
A private life is a happy life means your standards should be for you, not for a performance.
When you aim for good enough, you give yourself the freedom to actually communicate.
If you're afraid to make a mistake, you'll never say anything interesting in a new language.
You'll just say the safe things you know are perfect.
Remember, understandable beats impressive every single time in the real world.
It's a shift in perspective.
Instead of seeing good enough as a failure of quality, I should see it as a victory of momentum.
I'd rather have 10 good conversations in English than one perfect sentence that I was too afraid to even say.
Let's try a mini exercise for everyone listening.
Stop for a second and think.
What is one thing in your life right now?
Maybe a study task, a chore, or a message, where 80% effort already gives you 90% of the value.
What is the one thing where being useful is actually better than being flawless?
I'm thinking of my vocabulary list.
I've been trying to memorize the dictionary,
but really, knowing the most common 500 words is what gives me almost all my value in conversation.
Everything else is just over polishing.
That's a perfect realization.
But even when we know this, there is still a hidden cost to waiting that most people never calculate.
You mentioned a hidden cost earlier, and I've been sitting here trying to calculate it in my head.
If I spend an extra week perfecting a project, I'm losing seven days of my life.
But it's more than just time, isn't it?
It's the things I didn't do because I was so focused on this one thing.
While I've been obsessing over the perfect way to introduce this podcast
or the perfect way to explain a grammar point,
I've missed out on dozens of other opportunities to connect with our listeners.
It's like I'm paying a massive tax on my potential just to avoid a tiny bit of embarrassment.
That is exactly what economists call opportunity cost.
Every hour you spend over polishing a single sentence is an hour you aren't spending on a new idea,
a new conversation, or even just resting
so you can be creative tomorrow.
The world is moving at an incredible pace in 2026.
If you wait until you are 100% ready, the opportunity will have already passed you by.
The market will have changed, the conversation will have moved on, and your perfect work will be irrelevant.
In the digital age, speed is often a higher quality than perfection.
That feels very stressful, Emma.
It sounds like you're telling me to just rush everything so I don't miss out.
If I'm always worried about the opportunity cost, aren't I just trading one type of anxiety for another?
Now, instead of worrying about quality, I'm worrying about being too slow.
I don't want my life to feel like a race where I'm just throwing good enough things out the window as I drive past.
I want to feel like I'm building something that lasts.
It's not about rushing.
It's about effective momentum.
Think of it like a train.
It takes a lot of energy to get the train moving,
but once it's at cruising speed, it's much easier to maintain.
Perfectionism is like slamming on the brakes every five meters to check if the wheels are shiny.
You never get to the destination.
Spend effort only on what's truly worth it,
and the momentum of your growth is worth much more than the polish on a single project.
A private life is a happy life,
means you don't need the external validation of a perfect score to know you are moving in the right direction.
So the cost of waiting is that I'm essentially staying at the station while everyone else's train has already left.
I'm starting to see that my fear of being wrong is actually a fear of being seen in progress.
I want to arrive at the destination without anyone seeing me do the hard work of travelling.
I want the perfect result without the messy journey.
But if I don't accept the mess, I never actually leave the station.
Exactly.
We all want the highlight reel, but life happens in the raw footage.
The messy middle is where the actual transformation occurs.
It's where you make the mistakes
that teach you the most, and where you find the creative solutions you never would have found if you were just following a perfect plan.
The messy middle sounds like a place I've been trying to avoid my whole life.
It sounds uncomfortable.
It is uncomfortable, but it's also the only place where you are truly alive and growing.
The messy middle.
Honestly, Emma, that sounds like my worst nightmare.
My brain is wired to love the beginning,
the excitement of a new project,
and the end where everything is clean and finished.
But the middle?
That's where the English grammar gets confusing.
The design looks amateur, and the original vision feels like it's falling apart.
I usually stop right there because I assume the mess is a sign that I've failed.
I tell myself, if I were really good at this, it wouldn't look this bad.
Is the mess really a necessary part of the path, or am I just doing it wrong?
The mess is the most honest part of the path, Daniel.
Every great masterpiece looks like a disaster halfway through.
A half painted portrait looks like a ghost.
A half built house is just a pile of bricks and dust.
We've been conditioned by social media to see only the finished product,
so we think the ugly phase is a mistake.
But the middle is where the real work happens.
Spend effort only on what's truly worth it.
And the worth it part of the middle isn't the quality of the work, it's the quality of the effort.
You are training your brain to handle frustration, which is a much more valuable skill than being perfect.
So I shouldn't be judging my progress based on
how pretty the result looks while I'm in the thick of it.
That's hard to do.
When I hear myself struggling to find a word in English, I feel like I'm moving backward.
I feel like I'm losing my identity as a smart person because I'm making stupid mistakes.
I want to skip the mess
and just get to the part where I'm fluent
and confident, but you're saying that the stupidity of the middle is
actually the price of the wisdom at the end.
Precisely.
A private life is a happy life, means you don't have to show anyone your messy middle.
You can be bad at something in private until you are good at it in public.
The mess is your private laboratory.
If you try to make the middle look like the end,
you'll never experiment, you'll never take risks,
and you'll never find your unique voice.
You have to give yourself permission to be ugly for a while.
If you can't handle being a beginner, you'll never become a master.
Permission to be ugly.
I've never given myself that.
I've always demanded that my first draft be a final draft.
I guess that's why I have so many unfinished projects in my drafts folder.
I hit the messy middle, got scared by the ugliness, and walked away.
I thought I was protecting my standards,
but I was really just protecting my ego from the reality of hard work.
Your ego is the only thing that's afraid of the mess.
Your potential, however, thrives in it.
The middle is where you find out who you really are when things aren't going perfectly.
It's where resilience is born.
Alright, Emma.
I'm ready to stop hiding in the drafts.
I'm ready to embrace the mess and just get the thing done.
But how do I actually hit send when I still feel like it's not ready?
That brings us to our final challenge, the ship it mindset.
Okay, Emma.
I'm standing at the edge of the cliff.
I've accepted that perfection is a cage.
I understand the cost of waiting, and I'm even willing to be ugly in the messy middle.
But there is still that final terrifying moment when my finger is hovering over the send or post button.
That's when the what ifs come back at full volume.
What if I missed a glaring error?
What if I regret it tomorrow?
How do I actually develop the courage to just ship it when every bone in my body is telling me to check it just one more time?
You have to realize that ship it isn't an act of confidence.
It's an act of discipline.
One of the best ways to overcome that final hesitation is to set a nonnegotiable deadline.
Tell yourself, at 4PM, this email goes out no matter what.
By making the time more important than the quality, you take the power away from your inner critic.
Spend effort only on what's truly worth it,
and at the end of a project,
the most worth it thing is the completion, not the perfection.
A nonnegotiable deadline.
That forces the decision out of my hands.
But I know myself, Emma.
I'll hit send and then spend the next hour sweating, wishing I could pull the email back.
I'll probably wake up at 3AM thinking about a typo.
That's why you need the after ship rule.
No editing, no deleting, and no checking for twenty four hours.
Once it's out, it's out.
If you see a mistake later,
consider it your tuition fee, the small price you pay for the lesson of moving forward.
And here is a secret.
If you cringe at what you did tomorrow, congratulations.
That means you are already growing.
You are already a better version of yourself than the person who shipped that work yesterday.
If you cringe, you're growing.
I've never thought of it that way.
I always thought cringing was a sign of failure, but it's actually a sign of progress.
I'd rather be an imperfect human who is moving than a perfect ghost who is invisible.
A private life is a happy life means I don't need to perform for the whole world.
I just need to be honest with my own growth.
I'm ready to start shipping, and I'm ready to stop deleting.
That's the spirit.
Most people are so worried about their own mistakes that they won't even notice yours.
They are looking for value, not flaws.
And for our listeners, we want you to join this ship it movement with us.
Here is your cozy English challenge.
Pick one thing today that you've been polishing for too long.
Set a ten minute timer, finish it, and hit send or post.
Then, follow the after ship rule.
No deleting for twenty four hours.
Don't forget to download the full PDF script in the description.
It's a tool to help you grow, not a perfect document you need to fear.
Use it to find the phrases that help you speak your truth.
We want to hear from you in the comments.
Don't just tell us, what did you ship today?
Tell us, what did you survive?
What was the fear you walked through to get that task done?
Let's celebrate the survival of our perfectionism together.
Thank you for spending this quiet, imperfect time with us.
We'll be here for you in the next episode.
Take it one hour at a time.
Goodbye.
Goodbye, and stay cozy.