This is the story of a poor boy.
He had no money, he had no mobile phone,
he had no English books, but still,
he learned to speak English fluently and his life changed.
How did he do it?
Let me tell you his story.
The boy's name was Aman.
He lived in a small village.
His father was a farmer.
His mother worked in people's homes.
They were very poor.
Sometimes, they ate only one meal a day.
Amman worked in the fields after school.
He helped his mother clean houses.
He never complained, but he had one big dream.
Amman wanted to speak English.
Why?
Because in his school, rich boys laughed at him.
They spoke English.
He could not.
He felt small.
He felt stupid.
He felt alone.
But he made a decision.
I will learn English, he said, no matter how hard it is.
A man had no money for English classes.
He had no Internet, but he had one thing, his strong will.
He found old newspapers in the garbage.
He tried to read them.
He listened to English classes from outside the school window.
He wrote down words in a small notebook.
One word, every day.
He used a simple trick.
He spoke to himself in English.
He practiced daily.
He made mistakes.
He laughed at his own English, but he never stopped.
He listened to English songs on old radio.
He watched people's lips when they spoke English.
He copied them.
Slowly, he improved.
After six months, he could say simple sentences.
After one year, he could speak with tourists near his village.
They were surprised.
Aman felt happy.
He was not scared now.
He wanted to speak more.
Now, Aman wanted to help others.
He started teaching English to younger children under a tree for free.
He told them, you don't need money to learn English.
You need two things, time and effort.
One day, a teacher from the city came to his village.
He heard Amman speaking English.
He was shocked.
The teacher helped Aman get a scholarship.
Aman went to college.
He studied English.
He became a teacher.
Today, Aman teaches hundreds of students.
He speaks English every day.
People respect him.
He changed his life with English, without money, without coaching, just with hard work.
Maybe you are like Aman.
Maybe you don't have a lot, but you have a dream.
You can speak English.
You just need to start today.
One word.
One sentence.
One step.
Because your journey is hard, but not impossible.