The Cozy English.
Learn English slowly.
Welcome to the Cozy English.
I'm Emma, and I'm so glad you're here with us again today.
And I'm Daniel.
It's always nice to have this quiet moment with you.
We hope your day's been gentle so far.
Every week, we sit here together with our tea,
our thoughts, and a little bit of English practice to talk about life and growth.
And today's topic is something I think we all feel at some point.
Nothing changes if nothing changes.
That phrase really makes me think.
It sounds simple, but it's kind of uncomfortable too,
because it means if I keep doing the same things,
I'll keep living the same story.
Exactly.
It's that moment when you look around your life,
your job, your habits, your routines,
and realize that everything feels the same.
Not bad, just quietly repeating.
Days blend into each other, and you start to wonder, is this it?
I know that feeling.
It's not like you're unhappy, but there's this tiny voice in your head saying, maybe something should change.
Right.
But most of us wait.
We tell ourselves, I'll start when I have more time, or maybe next month.
But that next month becomes next year, and slowly we stop believing that things can be different.
So the real problem isn't that change is impossible.
It's that we get used to staying the same.
Yes.
Change asks for energy, courage, and sometimes a little discomfort.
But staying stuck also costs us something.
Our excitement, our curiosity, our growth.
I think about this a lot.
Sometimes I want to learn something new or try a different routine,
but then my brain says, what if you fail?
Or what if nothing changes anyway?
That's such a human thought.
We all want results right away.
But change usually begins quietly.
It starts the moment you decide to do something different,
even if it's small, like waking up ten minutes earlier,
saying no to one habit,
or finally taking the first step towards something that scares you.
So that's the real turning point, when you stop waiting and start doing, even just a little.
Exactly.
And that moment, even if it's tiny, is powerful.
Because once you take it, you're no longer