going to the grocery
store each week I go to the grocery
store to buy food for my family I get a
shopping cart from the front of the
store and I push the cart all around the
store the cart is large but when I am
finished shopping the cart is nearly
full the grocery store
is also called a
supermarket when I go shopping I start
out in the produce section of the
supermarket the produce section is where
the fresh fruits and vegetables are kept
I like to buy different kinds of fruit
such as apples oranges and bananas the
vegetables that I often buy are carrots
peas and corn I also buy tomatoes when
they are bright red in color
I often buy a bag of potatoes or a bag
of
rice after visiting the produce section
I go to the meat section here I buy
poultry such as chicken and turkey I
often buy seafood especially fish I also
buy beef and sometimes pork or lamb I
also visit the dairy section where I can
buy milk and
cheese sometimes I also o buy ice cream
or yogurt when I have finished in the
meat and dairy sections I then move to
the bakery section this is where loaves
of bread are baked and sold there are
many different kinds of bread in the
bakery section the bakery section also
sells pasta such as macaroni and
spaghetti and of course you can buy pies
cakes and cookies in the bakery section
these foods are very sweet and tasty
I also pick up a few other things at the
supermarket such as soap toothpaste and
cleaning supplies but sometimes I forget
to buy something that I plan to get
maybe I should make a list of the things
I need to buy
[Music]
h