Hey.
I need to reorder some flyers for my cafe's grand reopening next month.
Can you help me with that?
Sure. I can.
Let me check.
Oh, you're with the cozy corner. Right?
Didn't I design some flyers for you last year?
Yep. That's right.
But we've updated our logo and added a new menu so I'll need the design to reflect that.
Got it.
I can have those updated and printed by the end of the week.
By the way, would you like to see some paper options?
Maybe something sturdier than last time?
Oh, that's a great idea.
Let's go for it.
We need to come up with a new menu item for next month.
The chefs are suggesting something light and healthy,
like a quinoa salad with grilled vegetables.
That sounds nice, but we already have a few healthy options on the menu.
Maybe we should go for something more exciting,
like a fusion dish with bold flavors.
I thought about that too.
How about a spicy Korean chicken wrap?
It could be a unique twist and still keep it relatively healthy.
I love that idea.
Let's pitch it to the team during the menu meeting later.
I'm sure they'll be on board.
Hi, Ben.
It's Lisa from City Rentals.
Has Unit 305 been inspected for any maintenance issues yet?
Not completely.
The electrician was supposed to come yesterday to fix a faulty light in the living room
but had to reschedule for tomorrow.
We've checked the plumbing and heating,
and both are fine, but we're still waiting on the electrical work to be completed.
That's cutting it close.
The new tenants are moving in next Tuesday, and I really don't want any delays.
It's important we stay on schedule.
I understand.
I've already spoken to the electrician, and they assured me everything will be done by Friday.
We'll have it sorted in time for the move in.
Good afternoon.
This is Daniel Mitchell from GreenTech Solutions.
I'm calling to place an order for some equipment.
We need 50 laser printers and 200 ink cartridges, please.
The product codes are LP10 and IC25.
Thank you for the order, mister Mitchell.
I'm happy to let you know that we have a promotion going on right now.
You'll get free shipping for orders over $500, and the ink cartridges are currently 10% off.
That's fantastic news.
I'll pass it on to my purchasing department.
They'll be happy about the savings.