The Cozy English.
Learn English slowly.
Hello, dear friends, and welcome back to the Cozy English.
I'm Emma, and I'm so glad you're here with us again.
Hi, everyone.
I'm Daniel.
You know, Emma, I've been thinking a lot about today's topic.
It's kind of serious.
Right?
It is, but it's also important.
Today, we're talking about something that touches everyone, time.
More exactly, how not to waste it, because we're not young forever.
That sounds a little scary.
Maybe.
But think of it this way.
Time is the most precious gift we have.
We can earn more money.
We can buy more things, but we can never buy back time.
That's true.
Sometimes I feel like days just disappear.
I wake up, do a little work, check my phone, and suddenly it's evening.
Yes.
I know that feeling too.
It's almost like sand slipping through our fingers.
We don't notice until it's gone.
So the real question is, how do we use our time well?
That's the heart of it.
We use it by remembering that every hour is valuable.
Even simple moments, like talking with a friend, learning something new, or just enjoying a walk, are treasures.
I like that word, treasures.
It makes me think that even small things in daily life can be meaningful.
Exactly.
And here's something I've noticed.
When we see time as treasure, we live more carefully.
We choose better.
We don't let our hours just disappear without meaning.
That makes sense.
I guess I need to ask myself, am I spending time, or am I investing it?
Beautifully said, Daniel.
Spending means it's gone with nothing to show.
Investing means it grows into something, skill, joy, love, or memory.
So if I spend an hour learning English, it's an investment.
But if I spend an hour scrolling on my phone without thinking, it's just gone.
Yes.
And the more we see time this way, the more powerful our choices become.
You're right.
Time really is precious.
I don't want to waste it anymore.
None of us do.
And that's why this conversation matters.
Because once we see the value of time, we can start to live more fully, more wisely, and more joyfully.
Daniel, in the last section, we talked about time as treasure.
But there's something even more delicate about time.
Our youth.
Youth.
You mean being young, full of energy?
Exactly.
Youth is a gift.
When we're young, we think we have endless time.
We believe our bodies will always be strong.
Our energy will always return.
But the truth is youth doesn't last forever.
That makes me a little sad.
Because sometimes I do feel young, but other times, I already feel tired.
That's natural.
And it's not about fear.
It's about awareness.
When we're aware that youth is limited, we can use it wisely.
You know, I remember when I was a teenager,
I could stay up all night,
eat junk food, and still feel fine the next morning.
Now even one late night makes me feel like a zombie.
Yes.
That's such a clear reminder.
Our bodies change, and our energy changes too.
That's why wasting time becomes more costly as we grow older.
So you're saying we should take advantage of our energy while we still have it?
Exactly.
Not in a pressured way, but in a grateful way.
Youth is a season, like spring.
Flowers don't bloom forever.
But while they bloom, they bring beauty and life.
That's a beautiful picture.
But, Emma, isn't it also true that people can do meaningful things even when they're older?
Of course.
Every age has its own strength,
but youth is special because it gives us extra energy
and courage to build a foundation.
For example, learning languages, starting habits, or developing skills.
They all grow easier when you start earlier.
I see.
So if I waste my youth only on entertainment or laziness,
I might regret it later when I don't have the same energy.
Yes.
And regret is heavy.
That's why awareness now is so powerful.
It lets us use youth as a blessing instead of letting it slip away.
I think I needed this reminder.
Sometimes I tell myself, I'll do it later.
I have time.
But maybe I don't have as much time as I think.
Exactly.
That little voice, I'll do it later, is dangerous.
Later may come, but youth may not wait.
That hits me.
Maybe I should start now, not tomorrow.
Yes, Daniel.
And to our listeners, maybe you can ask yourselves, what is one thing I've been waiting to start?
Can I begin today while I still have energy?
That's powerful.
Youth isn't endless, but if we use it well, its impact can last a lifetime.
Beautifully said.
Youth is not forever, but what you do with it can echo forever.
Daniel, we've talked about time as treasure and how youth doesn't last forever.
But there's another challenge we face today, distractions.
Oh, yes.
I know this one too well.
My biggest enemy is my phone.
I pick it up just to check one message, and suddenly, forty minutes have disappeared.
Exactly.
Distractions are sneaky.
They don't take whole days at once.
They steal little pieces.
Ten minutes here, half an hour there, until suddenly the whole day is gone.
And the worst part is I don't even feel good after.
I just feel empty, like I wasted my energy on nothing.
Yes.
That's the trap.
Distractions give us the illusion of pleasure, but they rarely give us real satisfaction.
So, Emma, why do we fall into them so easily?
I think because distractions are easy, and meaningful things are often harder.
Watching videos feels effortless.
Studying, working, creating, that takes focus.
Our brains naturally choose the easy path.
That's true.
Sometimes, even when I plan to study, my hand just reaches for the phone, almost like a reflex.
Yes.
It becomes a habit, and habits are powerful.
But the good news is we can build new ones.
How?
One way is awareness.
When you notice yourself reaching for the phone,
pause and ask, is this really how I want to spend my next twenty minutes?
That question alone could save me a lot of time.
Yes.
Another way is replacement.
Instead of only removing distractions, give yourself something meaningful to fill the space,
like listening to a podcast, writing, or even resting.
So it's not just about stopping.
It's about choosing better.
Exactly.
And sometimes it helps to create little boundaries.
For example, I don't keep my phone near my bed at night.
That way, my mornings begin calm, not chaotic.
Oh, I always check my phone first thing.
No wonder my mornings feel messy.
You see?
Small changes can protect your time.
It's strange, isn't it?
We say we don't have time, but really, time is often hiding in the places we waste it.
That's true.
Distractions don't just steal time.
They also steal opportunities.
The chance to grow, to rest deeply, to connect with people we love.
That makes me think.
How many moments with family or with myself have I lost
because I was staring at a screen?
That's a powerful question.
And it's not about guilt.
It's about awareness.
When we see the cost of distractions, we can begin to take back our time.
Yes.
And maybe listeners can ask themselves too.
What's the biggest distraction in my life right now?
And what small step can I take to reduce it?
Exactly.
Because when we free ourselves from distractions, we don't just save time.
We give life back to ourselves.
Daniel, once we notice distractions and how they steal our time,
the next question is, what should we use that time for?
Right.
If I take away the phone, the videos, the endless scrolling, I suddenly have hours.
But then I wonder, what do I actually want to do with them?
That's the heart of the matter.
Choosing what truly matters.
Because time is limited, we can't do everything.
But we can choose the things that give life meaning.
That sounds beautiful, but also a little heavy.
What if I choose the wrong things?
That's a fair fear, but often the answer is simple.
Ask yourself, what will I be glad I did when I look back a year from now?
I like that.
A year from now, I don't think I'll remember the hours I spent watching funny clips,
but I'll remember the book I finished or the skill I learned.
Exactly.
Or the conversations you had, the people you helped, the memories you created.
Those are the treasures that stay.
It's true.
Some of my happiest memories are really simple.
Playing guitar with a friend, cooking dinner with my mom, or just taking a long walk.
Yes.
What matters most is often not complicated.
It's the things that connect us to ourselves and to others.
But, Emma, sometimes I feel pressure.
Everyone says, do something big, be successful, make money.
How do I know if what matters to me is enough?
That's a deep question.
I believe what matters is deeply personal.
For one person, it may be building a business.
For another, it's raising children with love.
For another, it's creating art.
What matters is not how the world measures it, but how your heart feels it.
So meaning isn't always loud.
Sometimes it's quiet.
Exactly.
And here's something I ask myself.
Does this give me life, or does it drain me?
If it gives me life, even if it's small, then it matters.
I see.
That means even something like practicing English for twenty minutes matters
because it connects me to my future self.
Yes.
Perfectly said.
Every small act that builds love, growth, or connection has value.
You know, this makes me want to make a little list of what truly matters to me right now just to keep it clear.
That's a wonderful idea.
And to our listeners, maybe you can do the same.
Write down three things that matter most to you this season.
Then ask yourself, am I giving them my best hours?
That's a little scary, but also exciting.
It is.
Because when you choose what truly matters, you don't just save time.
You create a life worth remembering.
Daniel, we've spoken about time, youth, distractions, and choosing what matters.
Now comes the final piece, how to live with both urgency and joy.
Urgency and joy?
Those sound almost opposite.
Urgency feels like pressure, and joy feels like freedom.
That's true.
But when they come together, they create a powerful way to live.
Urgency means remembering life is short.
Joy means celebrating life as a gift.
I see.
So urgency wakes us up, and joy keeps us alive while we're awake.
Exactly.
Without urgency, we waste time.
Without joy, we suffer through it.
But with both, every day becomes precious.
That makes me think of my grandfather.
He always told me, don't wait too long to live.
Tomorrow is never promised.
Wise words.
And yet many of us live as if tomorrow is guaranteed.
We say, I'll call my friend later.
I'll start my dream next year.
But life doesn't always wait.
That's true.
I lost a friend last year,
and I remember thinking I should have spent more time with him when I had the chance.
I'm sorry, Daniel.
That's a painful reminder.
But it also shows us why urgency matters,
not to scare us, but to remind us to love and act today.
And joy.
How do we bring that in?
Joy comes when we notice the simple gifts of the present moment.
Drinking tea, hearing laughter, learning something new, walking in the sun.
These moments when lived fully make urgency gentle, not heavy.
So urgency tells me, don't waste this moment.
And joy tells me, enjoy this moment.
Yes.
Together, they make life meaningful and beautiful.
You know, Emma, I think I've often lived with neither.
Sometimes I waste time without urgency.
Other times, I work hard without joy.
But now, I want both.
And that's the invitation for all of us,
to live as if time is precious
and to love as if every moment is a gift.
That makes me feel grateful right now, just sitting here, having this conversation.
Me too, Daniel.
And to our listeners, maybe you can ask, what is one way I can live today with urgency and joy?
I'll start by calling my mom tonight.
That feels both urgent and joyful.
That's perfect, and I think she'll be very happy.
As we close, let's take a moment together.
Time is passing.
Youth is not forever.
Distractions are always near, but you have the power to choose.
You can give your hours to what matters.
And when we do, we don't just fill time.
We live it fully, urgently, and joyfully.
Yes.
So, dear friends, maybe tonight or tomorrow morning,
pause and ask yourself, am I living the life I want to remember?
Thank you, Emma, and thank you, listeners.
Let's not waste our time.
We're not young forever.
Take care of your moments, and they will take care of you.
We'll see you next time here on the Cozy English.
Bye, everyone, and don't forget to live today.