The Cozy English.
Learn English slowly.
Hi. Hi, everyone.
It's so lovely to be with you again.
I'm Emma.
And I'm Daniel.
Thanks for joining us.
It's always a joy to share this quiet space with you.
How are you doing today?
I hope you're feeling calm, maybe sipping something warm or just taking a peaceful break for yourself.
It's your little moment to breathe and reflect.
I like that.
A moment to breathe.
I think we all need that more than we realize.
Sometimes life feels like we're always running towards something, but we don't even know what that something really is.
That's such a good way to put it.
We often think becoming the best version of ourselves means arriving at a perfect point,
having the right job, the right habits, the right mindset.
But truthfully, becoming your best self isn't a destination.
It's a journey that never stops.
So it's not about reaching some final version of yourself, but continuing to grow.
Exactly.
Think of it like this.
Every day, you're writing a new page in your own story.
Some days are full of color and excitement.
Other days are quiet or even messy.
But every page matters.
That's comforting.
Sometimes I feel like I should have figured everything out by now,
but maybe I'm just in the middle of my story, and that's okay.
That's more than okay.
Growth is never a straight line.
It's full of small steps, mistakes, and moments of realization.
Becoming your best self means learning, unlearning, and trying again.
I like that.
Learning, unlearning, and trying again.
It sounds more forgiving than chasing perfection.
It is forgiving.
The best version of you isn't perfect.
It's the version that keeps choosing to grow even when it's hard.
So maybe the goal isn't to arrive, but to stay curious about who we can still become.
Beautifully said, Daniel.
When we stop rushing to arrive and start embracing the process, we discover something powerful.
We're already becoming every single day.
That makes me feel lighter.
Like I can take it one day at a time without pressure.
That's exactly how it should feel.
Becoming your best self isn't about racing forward.
It's about waking up each day and saying, I'm still growing.
Emma, I've been thinking about what you said, that becoming your best self is a journey.
I guess the next question is, how do we even know who that best self is?
That's such an important question, Daniel.
I think it starts with self awareness.
Learning to look honestly at who you are, like standing in front of an inner mirror.
Inner mirror.
That's a powerful image.
So it's not about how others see us, but how we see ourselves.
Exactly.
We spend so much time adjusting our image for the world,
trying to be liked, to be right, to fit in.
But real growth begins when you can look at yourself without pretending,
seeing your strengths and your flaws, and accepting both.
That sounds hard sometimes.
When I look at my own mistakes,
I often feel guilty or disappointed even if I try to learn from them.
And that's okay.
Self awareness isn't about judging yourself.
It's about understanding yourself.
It's like cleaning a window.
At first, it's cloudy and uncomfortable.
But once it clears, you see your life more truthfully.
I like that image.
Cleaning the window.
Maybe that's why people say awareness is the first step to change.
Yes.
When you understand why you react,
why you avoid something, or why you hold yourself back,
you start to make better choices.
You stop living on autopilot.
I can relate to that.
There were times when I felt frustrated and didn't even know why.
Once I started writing my thoughts in a journal,
I realized I was chasing goals
that didn't really belong to me.
They were just things I thought I should want.
That's such a beautiful discovery.
Sometimes the best version of ourselves isn't about adding more.
It's about removing what doesn't belong.
The expectations, the noise, the pressure.
So becoming your best self isn't always about doing more,
but about seeing clearly who you already are and what truly matters.
Yes.
And the mirror inside you doesn't lie.
It shows what's real.
When you can face yourself with honesty and kindness, you stop trying to be perfect, and you start being true.
That makes me think.
Maybe the best version of me isn't someone new.
It's just me without the masks.
That's a perfect way to say it, Daniel.
When we learn to see ourselves clearly, that's when real growth begins.
Not from outside approval, but from inner understanding.
Daniel, have you ever noticed how people often wait for the right moment to change?
They wait for motivation, for the new year, for Monday, as if transformation only starts when life feels perfect.
That's so true.
I've done that so many times, telling myself, I'll start next week or when things calm down.
But that perfect time never really comes, does it?
No.
It doesn't.
The truth is change doesn't begin with motivation.
It begins with small, consistent choices.
It's less about waiting for the right mood and more about building the right habits.
So, like, what kind of small choices?
Simple ones.
Choosing to wake up a bit earlier,
to read instead of scroll, to speak kindly to yourself when things go wrong.
These small actions might look ordinary, but they build the foundation of who you're becoming.
That reminds me of when I started exercising again.
At first, I told myself I'd just do five minutes a day.
It felt almost too easy, but it worked.
Over time, those five minutes became thirty.
That's a perfect example.
The best version of you isn't built overnight.
It's shaped in quiet, daily choices that no one else sees.
Every small decision is a vote for the person you want to become.
I like that idea.
A vote for the person you want to become.
It turns small actions into something meaningful.
Yes.
When you choose progress over comfort, kindness over negativity, or discipline over excuses, you're rewriting your future in tiny steps.
It's also less stressful that way.
I used to think growth had to be dramatic,
like a total life change, but small,
steady actions feel more real and more possible.
That's the beauty of it.
When you focus on small choices, you stop chasing perfection and start practicing improvement.
It's not about being someone new tomorrow.
It's about being 1% better today.
I think that's something our listeners will really relate to, especially those who feel stuck.
It's a reminder that change doesn't need to be big to matter.
Yes.
Every small good decision is like a seed.
It may take time to grow,
but one day, you'll look back
and realize those little choices built the best version of you.
That makes me want to start something small today, even if it's just one tiny promise to myself.
And that's the perfect way to begin.
Because the best version of you isn't waiting somewhere far away.
It's being built quietly right now.
Emma, all this talk about small changes reminds me of people who completely turn their lives around.
I've always wondered what really makes that kind of transformation possible.
That's a beautiful question.
I once met a woman named Leah who taught me a lot about real transformation.
For years, she worked at a job she didn't love.
Every day, she told herself she wasn't good enough to do anything else until one day, something small changed.
What happened?
It was something ordinary, really.
She was having coffee with a friend who asked, when was the last time you felt proud of yourself?
That question stayed with her all night.
The next morning, she looked in the mirror and realized she didn't recognize the person she'd become.
Always tired, always afraid.
That sounds heavy, but also like a turning point.
It was.
That day, she made a simple decision.
Not to quit her job, not to change everything, just to do one brave thing each day.
Sometimes that meant saying no to extra work.
Sometimes it meant applying for a course she'd always wanted.
One brave thing each day.
That's powerful.
It sounds small, but it slowly rewrites who you believe you are.
Exactly.
After a year, she didn't just have new skills.
She had a new sense of self.
She said to me once, I didn't become a different person.
I just stopped hiding the real one.
That's such a beautiful line.
It reminds me that transformation isn't about becoming someone else.
It's about uncovering who you've always been underneath the fear.
Yes.
Real growth often looks quiet from the outside, but inside, it feels like the world opening up.
It's not a sudden jump.
It's a slow awakening.
And it starts with courage.
Not the loud kind, but the quiet courage to try again, to take one small step even when it's scary.
That's the kind that changes everything.
Leah's story reminds me that the best version of you isn't waiting for the perfect moment.
It begins when you do something brave, no matter how small.
I think that's something we can all carry with us.
One small act of courage each day.
It makes the idea of becoming your best self feel less like a dream and more like a choice.
Yes.
Because in the end, transformation doesn't happen overnight.
It happens every time you choose to believe there's more in you than your fear wants you to see.
Daniel, I think the most important part of becoming your best self is remembering this.
It's not about being perfect.
It's about being better, a little at a time.
That's true.
I used to think the best version of me meant always positive, always strong, never making mistakes.
But now I realize that kind of perfection just makes you tired and afraid to be real.
I love how you said that.
Real growth doesn't mean never falling.
It means learning to stand up with more grace each time.
You don't need to shine every day.
Some days, you just need to show up.
That's such a relief to hear.
I think people sometimes forget that becoming your best self also means accepting your worst moments,
learning from them instead of running away.
Yes.
The best version of you knows how to rest, forgive, and keep going.
It's the version that chooses kindness over judgment, especially toward yourself.
That's something I'm still learning.
When I fail, my first instinct is to be harsh with myself.
But lately, I've been trying to ask, what can I learn from this?
Instead of what's wrong with me.
That's growth, Daniel.
It's the voice of self compassion, the quiet strength that helps you become not only better, but happier.
So maybe the best version of ourselves isn't about doing everything right, but about doing things with more heart.
Exactly.
Growth looks different for everyone, but it always begins with love, patience, and courage.
The kind of courage that whispers, keep going.
You're doing fine.
That's something I want our listeners to remember too.
You don't need to wait for a perfect day or a perfect version of yourself.
You're already becoming just by trying.
Yes.
And the best version of you isn't someone you have to find.
It's someone you already are, just waiting to be cared for, understood, and trusted.
To everyone listening, thank you for sharing this quiet time with us today.
We hope this episode reminded you that growth doesn't need to be big or fast.
It just needs to be honest.
Take one small step each day, no matter how simple.
Read something new, take a walk, forgive yourself, or just breathe.
That's how you keep becoming.
Remember, you don't have to be perfect, just present.
You're already enough, and your journey matters.
Keep believing in the person you're becoming.
You're doing better than you think.
Thank you for listening to the cozy English.
Take care of yourself, and keep growing gently.
See you next time, friends.
Bye bye, and have a peaceful day.
Bye bye.