Hello. And welcome to Real Easy English
the podcast where we have real conversations in easy English to help you learn.
I'm Georgie.
And I'm Neil.
Don't forget that there's a video version of this podcast on our website, bbclearningenglish.com.
You can find subtitles to read along and you can download a free worksheet.
Hello, Neil.
Hi, Georgie.
Happy New Year.
Thank you.
Happy New Year to you too.
Today, we are talking about the start of a new year.
So we're going to talk about some of our plans for the new year
and we'll also make some New Year's resolutions.
So this is a tradition where people make promises to themselves for the new year.
They're difficult to keep, aren't they?
They are.
But we try anyway.
Exactly.
So are you excited about the new year, Neil?
I think so.
Twenty twenty six.
Can you believe it?
I cannot believe it.
Okay.
So have you got any big plans?
Well, I'm going to start the year with a big trip, actually, with my family.
We're going to South Africa because this is where my parents had their honeymoon
and my mom also used to live there for a while.
So it's a dream of hers to go with the whole family and she can show us around a bit.
What about you?
Well, I don't have any big plans yet, but it's an important year at school, especially for my daughter.
And so when she finishes that her school year
and her exams, maybe we'll do something special to mark that occasion.
So Georgie, it's impossible to talk about the New Year without mentioning resolutions.
So what are your resolutions?
I think my main one is to make fewer resolutions
because last year I made too many
and it was really hard to keep them
and it made me feel very bad about myself.
So this year, I'm just going to keep it simple.
Health, so running.
And language learning, Spanish, I need to do that.
But for running, I think this time I need a big goal.
So I'm a bit scared about it,
but I think I'm going to book a half marathon
because then I can make a training program and feel really motivated.
I think that's what I need.
I think that's a great idea.
What about you, Neil?
Any New Year's resolutions?
Well, usually, once Christmas and New Year are over,
we have the two darkest, saddest months of the year, January and February.
And normally, I really just wish that those months go away and that we get into spring.
But this year, I think I'm going to enjoy every day regardless,
you know, even if the weather is awful
and it's dark and cold, I still wanna get out there
and appreciate it rather than wish my life away.
So Neil, do you have any goals for this year?
So something you want to achieve?
I think I don't really want to take up something new.
Take up means start a new activity.
But I think my goal is to become good at something I like doing.
Right.
And what could that be?
So I like learning Spanish Mhmm.
But I'm not very good.
I'm not very dedicated.
And I'm always jealous of people who can speak really well.
And the same with my guitar.
I always wanna get better.
A goal could be to write a song and produce it.
And play it on this podcast.
All really unlucky.
I don't think anyone wants that.
Thank you for your honesty.
Right.
Let's recap the language we heard during the conversation.
We heard New Year's resolution, which is a promise you make to yourself at the start of a year to start doing something good or stop doing something bad.
We heard goals.
Now, goals are things that we say that we want to do and try to achieve them.
We also heard motivated, which is a feeling of really wanting to do something and doing it.
For example, I feel motivated to run a half marathon this year.
And we heard the expression to wish your life away.
If you wish your life away, you don't appreciate what's happening now.
You look far into the future.
That's it for this episode of Real Easy English.
Do you have a New Year's resolution?
We'd love to hear about it.
Email us at learningenglish@bbc.co.uk.
Is one of your New Year's resolutions to improve your English?
If so, go to our bbclearningenglish.com, where you can find all kinds of activities and quizzes to help you improve.
Goodbye for now.
Goodbye.