What is your English level right now?
Let's find out.
In this video, I'm going to ask you 30 questions.
Keep track of how many you answer correctly
because by the end, you'll know your CEFR English level from beginner to advanced.
Let's get started.
The first 10 questions are beginner level.
For each question, you'll see three sentences.
Choose the one that is grammatically correct.
Ready?
Question one.
Catherine don't like spicy food.
Catherine isn't like spicy food.
Catherine doesn't like spicy food.
The correct answer is Catherine doesn't like spicy food.
Question two.
This car is bigger than that one.
This car is more big than that one.
This car is the biggest that one.
The correct answer is this car is bigger than that one.
Question three.
Alex has a meeting in Monday.
Alex has a meeting on Monday.
Alex has a meeting at Monday.
The correct answer is, Alex has a meeting on Monday.
Question four.
Leo bought an umbrella.
Leo bought umbrella.
The correct answer is Leo bought an umbrella.
Question five.
I think it rains tonight.
I think it will rain tonight.
I think it is raining tonight.
The correct answer is, I think it will rain tonight.
Question six.
That backpack is mine.
That backpack is to me.
The correct answer is, that backpack is mine.
Question seven.
Did you watch the movie yesterday?
Have you watched the movie yesterday?
The correct answer is, did you watch the movie yesterday?
Question eight.
There is some rice in the bowl.
There are some rices in the bowl.
There is many rice in the bowl.
The correct answer is, there is some rice in the bowl.
Question nine.
Him called she last night.
He called her last night.
Her called him last night.
The correct answer is he called her last night.
Question 10.
They have studied English for five years.
They have studied English since five years.
They have studied English from five years.
The correct answer is they have studied English for five years.
Congratulations.
You've now finished the beginner section of the test.
If you got seven or more correct, you're likely a one.
If you got nine or more, you're at least a two.
Let's continue.
The next 10 questions are intermediate level.
Question one.
You have must to complete your homework.
You must completing your homework.
You must complete your homework.
The correct answer is you must complete your homework.
Question two.
Lena never gives attention in class.
Lena never pays attention in class.
Lena never throws attention in class.
The correct answer is Lina never pays attention in class.
Question three.
Have you ever visited Europe?
Did you ever visited Europe?
Have you ever visiting Europe?
The correct answer is, have you ever visited Europe?
Question four.
If we leave early, we'd arrive on time.
If we leave early, we'll arrive on time.
If we leave early, we'd have arrived on time.
The correct answer, if we leave early, we'll arrive on time.
Question five.
Emma speaks English fluent than her brother.
Emma speaks English more fluent than her brother.
Emma speaks English more fluently than her brother.
The correct answer is Emma speaks English more fluently than her brother.
Question six.
To read books is my favorite hobby.
Reading books is my favorite hobby.
To reading books is my favorite hobby.
The correct answer is reading books is my favorite hobby.
Question seven.
My partner hardly never eats meat.
My partner never hardly eats meat.
My partner hardly ever eats meat.
The correct answer is my partner hardly ever eats meat.
Question eight.
Alex often forgets to lock the door.
Alex often forgets locking the door.
Alex often forgets to locking the door.
The correct answer is Alex often forgets to lock the door.
Question nine.
Daniel should have tell his parents sooner.
Daniel should have been telling his parents sooner.
Daniel should have told his parents sooner.
The correct answer is, Daniel should have told his parents sooner.
Question 10.
Could you give me a lift to the station?
Could you give me to the station a lift?
Could you give me a lift at the station?
The correct answer is, could you give me a lift to the station?
Great job.
You've now completed the intermediate section.
If you got seven or more correct, you're likely b one.
If you got nine or more correct, you're likely b two.
Now, let's move to the final section.
These last 10 questions are advanced level.
Question one.
It's freezing outside, isn't it?
It's freezing outside, isn't he?
It freezing outside, isn't it?
The correct answer is, it's freezing outside, isn't it?
Question two.
The author's explanation was deliberately, leaving readers to draw their own conclusions.
Obvious, ambiguous, clear.
The correct answer is ambiguous.
Question three.
By this time next year, she, at her new job for five years, will have been working.
Will work.
Worked?
The correct answer is, will have been working.
Question four.
Amelia's dream of becoming a singer never quite turned up, panned out, kicked off.
The correct answer is panned out.
Question five.
To have wasted two hours, Mike finally started his essay.
He had wasted two hours, Mike finally started his essay.
Having wasted two hours, Mike finally started his essay.
The correct answer is, having wasted two hours, Mike finally started his essay.
Question six.
The guide suggests booking your tickets at least three months.
Ego.
In advance.
Beforehand.
The correct answer is in advance.
Question seven.
Jordan is such an inspiring individual.
Jordan is such inspiring an individual.
Jordan is so an inspiring individual.
The correct answer is Jordan is such an inspiring individual.
Question eight.
After reviewing the evidence, the manager asked the team decision, report, verdict.
The correct answer is decision.
Question nine.
When Liam received the promotion, he was absolutely assio, ecstatic, annoyed, confused.
The correct answer ecstatic.
Question 10.
No matter how difficult the project appears, keep in mind that you are beats Confident.
Unprepared.
Careless.
The correct answer is confident.
Congratulations.
You've successfully completed the advanced level.
If you got seven or more correct, you're likely c one.
If you got nine or more, you're probably c two.
Great job for completing the test.
If you enjoyed this video, don't forget to like, subscribe and share it with someone learning English.
Thanks for watching and I'll see you in the next one.